Erwin Chargaff Papers 1929-1992 Mss.B.C37
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Photographs, 1935-1977; 1.75 linear feet
  - The Use of Capillary Columns for the Separation of Some Closely Related Positional Isomers Methyl Linoleate by Gas Chromatography, 1960 (Box 115)
  - UV Inactivation of DNA Primer Activity, 1962 (Box 115)
  - "Van Leeuwen, Elisabeth Josephina Maria", [5 Jun. 1961] (Box 115)
  - "Vischer, Ernst Benedikt", 1945 (Box 115)
  - Weizmann Institute, 1963 (Box 115)
  - What Really Is DNA? Remarks on the Changing Aspects of a Scientific Concept, [1968] (Box 115)
  - Yugoslavia. Serbian Academy of Science in Belgrade, June 22, 1970 (Box 115)
- Series VIa. Photographs and Negatives, 1921-2002; 11 boxes: 2 linear feet
  Prints, negatives and slides. The majority of the prints are portraits of Chargaff or photographs of people, places or events. There are some at events where Chargaff is receiving awards, such as the National Medal of Science. Many of these photographs are of unidentified events and/or undated. These are arranged either as photographs of Chargaff, dated and undated, or photographs of people, places and events, also dated or undated. Because of the volume of these photographs, there are generally two boxes for each topic, one holding photographs in loose-leaf form, the other holding loose photographs in a box.
  - Chargaff, Erwin, undated (Box 142)
  - Chargaff, Erwin, undated (Box 143)
  - Chargaff, Erwin, 1921-2001 (Box 144)
  - Chargaff, Erwin, 1928-1999 (Box 145)
  - Identified People, Places, Events, 1950, 1959, 1996 (Box 146)
  - Identified People, Places, Events, Bulk, 1971-1974; 1949, 1952, 1971-1974 (Box 147)
  - Identified People, Places, Things, undated (Box 147)
  - Photographs, Removed from Correspondence, Bulk, 1997-2002; 1976, 1997-2002 (Box 148)
  - Unidentified People, Locations and Events, Bulk, 1987-1998; 1951, 1977, 1987-1998, undated (Box 148)
  - Unidentified People, Locations and Events, 1959-1999 (Box 149)
  - Unidentified People, Locations and Events, undated (Box 150)
  - Unidentified Slides, undated (Box 151)
  - Unidentified Slides Nos 126-269, undated (Box 152)
  - People, Places, Events, Bulk, 1990-1999; 1966,1974, 1990-1999 (Box 153 (OVERSIZED))
  - Photographs Removed from Correspondence, 1999 (Box Box 154 (OVERSIZED))
  - Photographic Album of Erwin Chargaff, 1990 (Box Box 154 (OVERSIZED))
- Series VII. Audiovisual, 3 boxes: .5 linear feet
  Audiotapes, CDs, and videotapes, including many of Chargaff's television and radio appearances in Europe.
  - Audiovisual Materials Box 1 (Box Box 129)
    Format
    Contains 19 audio cassette tapes and 2 video cassette tapes labeled in German.
  - Audiovisual Materials Box 2 (Box 130)
    Contains 1 video cassette tape, 14 audio cassette tapes and 4 compact disks labeled in German.
- Series VIII. Awards and Certificates, 1958-2001; 7 boxes: 4 linear feet
  Awards, trophies, rosettes, and certificates, including the National Medal of Science.
  - Awards and Certificates Box 1 (Box 131)
    Contents
    Contains 9 medals from Columbia University, Societe de Chimie Biologique, American Society of European Chemists and Pharmacists, other.
  - Awards and Certificates Box 2 (Box 132)
    Contains 4 medals from University of Tokyo, Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher Leopoldina, other.
  - Awards and Certificates Box 3 (Box 133)
    Contains 2 notecards from the National Academy of Sciences and American Association for the Advancement of Science, and 7 medals from the National Medal of Science, Bertner Foundation, Columbia University, New York Academy of Medicine, Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher, other.
  - Awards and Certificates Box 4 (Box 134)
    Contains American Chemical Society membership pin, National Medal of Science pin, and Preis der Stadt Wien pin.
  - Awards and Certificates Box 5, 1964 (Box 135)
    Contains Heineken Prize and related news clipping.
  - Awards and Certificates Box 6, 1960-2001 (Box 136)
    Contains certificates from American Chemical Society, Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center, Royal Society of Chemistry and State of Texas (Honorary Citizen.)
  - Awards and Certificates Box 7, 1959-2001 (Box 137)
    Contains certificates from Columbia University and other organizations, primarily written in German.
  - National Medal of Science Award, 1974 (Box 156 (OVERSIZED))
  - Awards and Certificates Oversize Folder, 8.0
- Series IX. Lecture Notes, 1942-1985; 3 boxes: 1.25 linear feet
  Chargaff's lecture notes, including his Jesup Lectures at Columbia University as well as his speeches at professional conferences and awards ceremonies. This series is arranged alphabetically by lecture title. The lecture notes are primarily handwritten and, for the most part, are in English and German. Each provides not only the dates but also the locations where Chargaff gave each lecture.
  - About the RNA, 1959 (Box 138)
  - "The Age of Science" over "The Scientific Age", 1985 (Box 138)
  - Allmacht und Ohnmacht der Naturwissenschaften, 1980 (Box 138)
  - Ann Arbor Symposium, 1956 (Box 138)
  - Appreciation of Harvey Society on Todd's Lecture, 1951 (Box 138)
  - Aspects of Cell Chemistry Course, 1955-1957 (Box 138)
  - Aspects of Chemistry of the Genetic Material, 1960 (Box 138)
  - Aspects of Nucleic Acid Fractionation, 1958 (Box 138)
  - Aspects of Nucleotide Sequence in DNA, 1959 (Box 138)
  - Aspects of Nucleotide Sequence in Nucleic Acids, 1958 (Box 138)
  - Aspects of the Complementarity of DNA Strands, 1970 (Box 138)
  - Aspects of the Nucleotide Sequence in Nucleic Acids, 1963, 1965 (Box 138)
  - Base Composition of DNA and RNA in Various Species, 1956 (Box 138)
  - Beating the Drum for Small Science, 1982 (Box 138)
  - Bedroht die biologische Forschung die Zukunft des Menschen, 1984 (Box 138)
  - Betrachtungen uber Desoxyribonukleinsaure aks Schablone oder Text, 1968 (Box 138)
  - Biological Oxidation of Inositols, 1949, 1951 (Box 138)
  - Bitter Fruits of the Tree of Knowledge, The, 1972 (Box 138)
  - Blood Coagulation, 1942-1947 (Box 138)
  - Books for Cell Chemistry Class, 1949, 1952 (Box 138)
  - Cellular Control Mechanisms and Their Uncoupling, 1959 (Box 138)
  - Chem. and Phys. Nature of the Gene, 1961 (Box 138)
  - Chemical Composition of the Nucleic Acids from Carcinoma from Human Liver and from Normal Human Tissue, 1950 (Box 138)
  - Chemistry and Metabolism of Purines and Pyrimidines, 1959 (Box 138)
  - Chemistry of Fats and Lipids, 1953, 1955, 1956, 1957, 1958 (Box 138)
  - Chemistry of the Cell, 1944, 1949, 1950 (Box 138)
  - Chemistry of the Cell Advanced Graduate Course, 1949-1952 (Box 138)
  - Chemistry of Thromboplastic Protein, 1944 (Box 138)
  - Chimie des Acides Lucleiques, La, 1965 (Box 138)
  - Clinic, Einstein Medical School, 1959 (Box 138)
  - Coagulants and Anticoagulants, 1949 (Box 138)
  - Combined Clinic, "[undecipherable] Errors of Metabolism" - Chemical Basis of Genetics, 1960 (Box 138)
  - Composition and Structure of Nucleic Acids, 1950 (Box 138)
  - Consequences of Sequential Specificity and the Insufficiency of Coding Systems, 1959 (Box 138)
  - Current Dilemma of Life Sciences, The, 1978 (Box 138)
  - Development of Biochemistry in the 20th Century, 1974 (Box 138)
  - Discussion Paper on Nucleic Acids, 1955 (Box 138)
  - Economy of the Cell, The, 1950 (Box 138)
  - Einige Bemerkungen uber Evolution aus biochemischer Sicht, 1973 (Box 138)
  - Einleitende Bemerckungen, 1976 (Box 138)
  - Falscher Messias - Naturwissenschaft als Beruf und als Religionsersatz, 1983 (Box 138)
  - Fats, Lipids, Etc., 1942 (Box 138)
  - Few Things I Know and Many I Don't, A, 1975 (Box 138)
  - Few Things I Remember and Many I Have Forgotten, A, 1984 (Box 138)
  - Few Unorthodox Remarks about Science as the Savior of the World, A, 1981 (Box 138)
  - First Steps Towards a Chemistry of Heredity, 1958 (Box 138)
  - Fluch des Machbaren, Der, 1986 (Box 138)
  - Formation of [unreadable] Acid from Deoxyribonucleic Acid, 1952 (Box 138)
  - gegenwaertige Stand des Problems der Blutgerinnung, Der, 1943 (Box 138)
  - Gene Technology - Is It Feasible, Is It Desirable?, 1979 (Box 138)
  - Genetics Course, First Year, 1961 (Box 138)
  - Glycogen and Nucleoprotein Fractions of Tubercle Bacilli, 1947 (Box 138)
  - Graduate Student Course: Available Literature - How to Go About Finding Information, 1962-1964 (Box 138)
  - Great Dilemma of the Life Sciences, The, 1975 (Box 138)
  - Hans T. Clarke Commemoration, 1972 (Box 138)
  - Hemophiliac Clotting Defect in a Female, 1945 (Box 138)
  - How the Nucleic Acids Were Born, 1976 (Box 138)
  - Humble Beginnings of Molecular Biology, 1972 (Box 138)
  - Impact of Biochemistry on Genetics, 1975 (Box 138)
  - In Memoriam David H. Momberg, 1960 (Box 138)
  - Introduction for [unreadable] Conference, 1951 (Box 139)
  - Introduction to Biochemistry Course, 1971 (Box 139)
  - Introduction to Cellular Clinic on NA [Nucleic Acids], 1951
  - Introduction to du Vigneaud Talk at Pirquet Society, 1964 (Box 139)
  - Introductory Remarks, Horwitz Prize Dinner, 1968 (Box 139)
  - Investigation of Phospholipid Composition in Minute Amounts, 1949 (Box 139)
  - Lipoproteins, 1944 (Box 139)
  - Lipoproteins, 1946 (Box 139)
  - Lipoproteins and the Problem of Conjugated Proteins, 1950 (Box 139)
  - Methodical Observation on the Study of Nucleic Acid, 1949 (Box 139)
  - Mode of Action of Ribonuclease, 1954 (Box 139)
  - N.A., 1967 (Box 139)
  - Naive Look at Reductionism in Biology, A, 1975 (Box 139)
  - Natur der Menschen und die Natur der Naturwissenschaften, Die, 1985 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acid Chemistry: Biochem. Grad. Students, 1966, 1967 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids, 1955 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids - Chemistry and Biology, 1969 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids and Nucleoproteins, 1948, 1950, 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954, 1955 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids and Nucleoproteins, 1954 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids and the Concept of Biological Information, 1958 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids and the Problem of Biological Information, 1960, 1961 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids of Microorganisms, The, 1952 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids, Nucleoproteins, Cell Division, 1952, 1956, 1958-1960, 1962, 1964, 1967-1968 (Box 139)
  - Nucleic Acids: Their Life and Death, 1979 (Box 139)
  - Nucleoproteins and Nucleic Acids, 1959 (Box 139)
  - Nucleoproteins and Prosthetic Groups, 1954 (Box 139)
  - On Biological Consequences of Base-Pairing in Nucleic Acids, 1965 (Box 139)
  - On Chemistry of the Thromboplastic Effect, 1949 (Box 139)
  - On Concept of a Template, 1967 (Box 139)
  - On Concept of a Template, 1967 (Box 139)
  - On Design of Hearing Aids for the Morally Deaf, 1969 (Box 139)
  - On Fashions of Science, 1976 (Box 139)
  - On Fats and Function of Inositol, 1955 (Box 139)
  - On Microlipids of Nervous Tissue, 1958 (Box 139)
  - On Problem of Nucleoproteins, 1953 (Box 139)
  - On Problem of Strand Separation in DNA, 1968, 1969 (Box 139)
  - On Some of the Advantages of Smallnes in Scientific Research, 1981 (Box 139)
  - On Some of the Biol. Consequences of Base-pairing in Nucleic Acids, 1966 (Box 139)
  - On Some of the Biological Consequences of Base-pairing in Nucleic Acids, 1966 (Box 139)
  - On Uses of Nucleases, 1976, 1979 (Box 139)
  - Paradox of Biochemistry, The, 1968 (Box 139)
  - Problem der Biosynthese der Nukleinsaure, Das, 1973 (Box 139)
  - Problem of Nucleotide Sequence in Deoxyribonucleic Acids, The, 1960 (Box 139)
  - Problem of Sequence Analysis in Nucleic Acids, The, 1959 (Box 139)
  - Problem of Specificity and the Carriers of Biological Information, The, 1959 (Box 139)
  - Probleme der Strangtrennung in DNA, 1969 (Box 139)
  - Problems in Biosynthesis of DNA, 1974 (Box 139)
  - Problems in the Nucleotide Sequence of Deoxyribonucleic Acid, 1961 (Box 139)
  - Problems in the Strand Separation of DNA, 1971 (Box 139)
  - Problems in the Strand Separation of DNA: Preparation of Complementary Strands, 1969 (Box 139)
  - Problems in the Structure of Nucleic Acids, 1950 (Box 139)
  - Problems in the Template Function of DNA, 1968 (Box 139)
  - Problems in the Template Function of DNA, 1968 (Box 139)
  - Purpural[?] Clinic, 1944 (Box 139)
  - Recent Procedures for the Study of Lipoproteins, 1950 (Box 139)
  - Recent Studies in Inositol, 1952 (Box 139)
  - Recent Studies in Nucleotide Arrangement of Deoxyribonucleic Acids, 1959-1960 (Box 139)
  - Recent Studies in Rapidly Labeled RNA in Bacteria, 1964, 1965 (Box 139)
  - Recent Studies in Ribonucleic Acids, 1959 (Box 139)
  - Recent Studies on Chemistry and Biology of the Nucleic Acids, 1966 (Box 139)
  - Recent Studies on Nucleotide Sequence in DNA, 1963 (Box 139)
  - Recent Work on Lipoproteins as Cellular Constituents, 1947 (Box 139)
  - Recent Work on Nucleoproteins, 1957 (Box 139)
  - Recent Work on Strand Separation in DNA, 1970 (Box 139)
  - Regularities and Differences in the Nucleic Acid Field, 1951 (Box 139)
  - Remarks on Genetic Engineering and Recombinant DNA, 1976 (Box 139)
  - Remarks on the Current Revulsion from Science, 1971 (Box 139)
  - Remarks on the Limits of Science, 1977-1979 (Box 139)
  - Remarks Opening Genetics Symposium, 1967 (Box 139)
  - Remarks to Burnet's "Concepts of Autoimmune Disease", 1966 (Box 139)
  - Remarques sur le "Desordre Ordonne" des Acides Nucleiques, 1961 (Box 139)
  - Remarques sur la Desordre Ordonne des Acides Nucleiques, 1961 (Box 139)
  - Role of Lipids in Blood Coagulation, 1948 (Box 139)
  - Schwere Alternativen, 1980 (Box 140)
  - Separation and [Estimation] of Nucleic Acid Degradation Products, 1949 (Box 140)
  - Sequence Problems in the Deoxyribonucleic Acids, 1961 (Box 140)
  - Slides for Faraday Society, London, undated (Box 140)
  - Some of the Problems Facing the Life Sciences, 1979 (Box 140)
  - Structure and Function of Nucleic Acids, 1956 (Box 140)
  - Structure and Function of Nucleic Acids, The, 1953 (Box 140)
  - Structure Problems in Nucleic Acids, 1962 (Box 140)
  - Studies in Structure of Nucleic Acids, 1955 (Box 140)
  - Studies in the Chemistry of Nucleic Acids and the Mechanism of their Enzymatic Degradation, 1949 (Box 140)
  - Studies in the Composition and Properties of Nucleic Acids, 1951 (Box 140)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins and on the Fractionation of Nucleic Acids, 1955, 1958 (Box 140)
  - Studies on Nucleoproteins and the Fractionation of Deoxyribonucleic Acid, 1953, 1954 (Box 140)
  - Studies on the Biological Significance of Low-Energy Transphosphorylation in E. Coli, 1973, 1974 (Box 140)
  - Studies on the Dynamics of Chloroplast Formation in [undecipherable], 1964 (Box 140)
  - Studies on the Fractionation and Composition of Deoxyribonucleic Acid, 1953 (Box 140)
  - Studies on the Structure of Deoxypentose Nucleic Acids, 1952 (Box 140)
  - Studies on Thromboplastic Proteins and Lipids, 1954 (Box 140)
  - Studies on Thromboplastic Proteins and Lipids, undated (Box 140)
  - Sur la Specificite Chimique des Acides Nucleiques, 1949 (Box 140)
  - Symposium on "Conjugated Proteins": Introductory Remarks, 1953 (Box 140)
  - Symposium on "Man-Made Man", 1964 (Box 140)
  - Template Functions in Enzymatic DNA Synthesis, 1972 (Box 140)
  - Template Functions of Native and Denatured DNA and the Problem of Transcription, 1969 (Box 140)
  - Traum der Vernunft erzeugt Ungeheuer, Der, Undated (Box 140)
  - Uber den gegenwartigen Stand der Chemie der Nukleinsauren, 1956 (Box 140)
  - Uber den Zustand der reinen Naturforschung in unserer Zeit, 1979 (Box 140)
  - Uber die Eignung der Naturwissenschaften als Stutzpunkt unserer Kultur, 1981 (Box 140)
  - Uber die Grenzen der Naturwissenschaften, 1976 (Box 140)
  - Uber die Nutzlichkeit der Nukleasen, 1977 (Box 140)
  - Uber Licht und Zweilicht in den Naturwissenschaften, 1973 (Box 140)
  - Umrisse Einer Neuen Hoffnung, 1985 (Box 140)
  - Universal Regularities in the Composition of Ribonucleic Acid and their Bearing on Template Function (Box 140)
  - Untitled, 1972 (Box 140)
  - Untitled, 1973 (Box 140)
  - Untitled "Cleveland", 1951 (Box 140)
  - Untitled Lecture, University of Toronto, Student Discussion, 1936 (?) (Box 140)
  - What Is the Use of Science, 1974 (Box 140)
  - What Really is DNA?, 1968 (Box 140)
  - Zoology Colloquium, 1951 (Box 140)
- Series X. Personal Papers, [1880]-1985; 1 box: .25 linear feet
  Telegrams, letters, certificates, documents and other papers relating to Chargaff and his family, including several documents from pre-war Austria. This series is arranged in alphabetical order by name and then by subject. Most of this series is in German.
  - Chargaff, Erwin: Monthly Street Car Pass, 1928 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Erwin: Newly Appointed Professors Columbia University, 1938 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Erwin: Obituaries, 2002 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Erwin: Subway Pass, 1930 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Erwin: University Gradebook, 1923-1924 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Grete: Letter, 1949 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Grete: Telegram to Erwin Chargaff, 1934 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Hermann: Austrian Citizenship, 1921 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Hermann: Austrian Passport, 1925 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Hermann: Birth Certificate (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Hermann: Heimatschein, 1927 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Hermann: Obituary, 1934 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Hermann: Rental Agreement, 1921 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Thomas, 1987 (Box 141)
  - Chargaff, Vera: Letters, 1949, 1989 (Box 141)
  - Expenses, undated (Box 141)
  - Harmick, Stephen M., Law Offices of, 2002 (Box 141)
  - Medical, 1999-2001 (Box 141)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 141)
  - References, 1988, 1998 (Box 141)